On Christmas Eve, many years ago...
多年以前的某个圣诞夜
...I lay quietly in my bed.
我静静的躺在床上
I did not rustle the sheets.
我没有翻来覆去
I breathed slowly and silently.
也没有心浮气燥
I was listening for a sound I was afraid I'd never hear.
我仔细听着 害怕再也听不到…
The ringing bells of Santa 's sleigh.
圣诞老人雪橇上的铃声
All right. All right, Sarah, you had your water.
好了，好了 你喝完了水，是吗?
Now let's get you upstairs and into bed.
该上楼睡觉啦
But-- But-- But, I have to--
但…但…我得…
He said Santa would have to fly faster than light...
他说圣诞老人得飞的比光速还快…
to get to every house in one night. And to hold everyone's presents...
才能在一个晚上到每户人家去 他的雪橇也得和一艘货船一样大
...his sled would be bigger than an ocean liner.
才能装的下每个人的礼物
Your brother said that?. He was just kidding you. He knows there's a Santa.
你哥哥是这么说的? 他是说笑,他知道圣诞老人是怎样的
He said he wasn't sure. He wasn't sure if Santa was for real.
他说他不确定 是不是真的有圣诞老人
Of course Santa is real. He's as real as Christmas itself.
当然有啦,就像圣诞节也是真的呀
But he won't come until you're sound asleep, young lady.
但是如果不好好睡觉 圣诞老人就不会来
Sweet dreams.
祝好梦
Santa will be here before you know it.
圣诞老人很快就会来
So go to sleep.
快睡吧
""Stark, barren.
史塔克 和 拜伦(作者)
Decoid of life.""
无生命迹象
He's gotta be asleep by now.
大概已经睡着了
He used to stay awake all night waiting for Santa.
他以前总是不睡, 要等圣诞老人
Think those days are just about over.
以前的日子都过去了
That would be sad if that were true.
如果真是这样,那也真伤心
Yeah, an end of the magic.
对呀,童真不再
Merry Christmas, sweetheart.
圣诞快乐,甜心
See, he's out like a light.
他睡的真熟
An express train wouldn't wake him up now.
就算火车来也吵不醒
""End of the magic ""?
童真不再！
All aboard!
上车咯!
Well?. You coming?.
你…要上车吗?
Where?.
去哪儿?
Why, to the North Pole, of course.
当然是去北极啦!
This is the Polar Express.
这是极地特快
The North Pole?.
北极?
I see.
我明白了
Hold this, please.
请替我拿一下
Thank you.
谢谢
Is this you?.
这是你吗?
-Yeah. -Well, it says here...
- 是的 - 这上说…
...no photo with a department-store Santa this year, no letter to Santa.
今年没去商场和圣诞老人拍照 也没写信给他
And you made your sister put out the milk and cookies.
还叫你妹妹也不要写…
Sounds to me like this is your crucial year.
看来今年是你的关键年
If I were you, I would think about climbing onboard.
如果我是你,就会立刻上车
Come on, come on. I've got a schedule to keep.
快,快,快,我赶时间…哇!
Suit yourself.
随你吧
'Cause that's the way things happen On the Polar Express
在极地特快上 事情就是这样子的
Whoo, whoo, the whistle blows That's the sound of her singing
呜~呜~汽笛响 是她唱歌的声音
Ding, ding, the bell will ring Golly, loo at her go
叮~叮~铃声响 天哪，看着她走
You wonder if we'll get there soon Anybody's guess
你觉得如果我们很快到达 谁来猜一猜…
'Cause that's the way things happen On the Polar Express
在极地特快上 事情就是这样子的
When we get there We'll scream, ""Yay!""
当我们到那里 就会尖叫，“噢，耶”
We'll arrive with A bang, bang, bang
我们到达那里 附和着邦~邦~邦
Boom, boom, boom Laughing all the way
还有噗~噗~噗 路上一直说笑着
With a comfy seat and lots to eat Boy, it's just the best
有个舒服的位子和很多吃的 天哪，这真是最好的
Wish it would 't ever have to end
希望永远不要结束
With a little luck, we'll be on time There's no need to stress
加上一点运气，我们会准时到的 没有必要有压力
'Cause that's the way things happen On the Polar Express
在极地特快上 事情就是这样子的
Hey. Hey, you. Yeah, you. Do you know what kind of train this is?
嗨,嗨,叫你呢 这是哪一种火车,你知道吗?
Train. Do you know what kind of train this is? Do you?
火车，这是哪一种火车,你知道吗?
Of course.
当然
It's a magic train.
这是魔法火车
-We're going to the North Pole. -I know it's a magic train.
- 我们要去北极 - 我当然知道是魔法火车!
It's a Baldwin 2-8-4 S3-class steam locomotive...
这是鲍温284S3系列, 蒸气动力火车
built in 1921 at the Baldwin Locomotice Works. It weighs 456,100 pounds and....
鲍温公司1931年制造, 重456,100磅…
Are we really going to the North Pole?
我们真的要去北极?
-Hey, look! -Isn't that wonderful?
- 嗨，快看呀！ - 是不是很漂亮?
Herpolsheimer's!
贺伯山莫斯!
Wow, look at all those presents. I want all of them.
哇～好多礼物! 我全部都要
It's so Christmassy and cozy and beautiful!
有圣诞夜的气氛, 好温馨,也很漂亮
Tickets.
车票
Tickets, please.
请拿出车票
Try your pocket.
摸摸你的口袋
Try your other pocket.
另一个口袋
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你
Hey, watch out, there.
喂,小心点儿
That is a public-address microphone. It is not a toy.
呃呃～那是公共地址播音机, 不是玩具
Boy, that guy sure likes to show off.
那家伙真爱炫耀
Look what that wise guy punched on my ticket.
看他在我车票上打了什么了!
""L-E."" What the heck does that mean?. -Next stop, 11244 Edbrooke.
LE,是啥意思? 下一站 艾布克街11344号
We're heading for the other side of the tracks.
我们正驶往铁路的另一端
Well. You coming?
你…要来吗?
It's just another pickup.
只是停下来载人
That's weird. I thought you were supposed to be the last one.
奇怪! 我已为你是最后一位乘客
Why, to the North Pole, of course.
当然是去北极啦!
This is the Polar Express.
这是极地特快
Suit yourself.
随你吧
Hey, that kid wants to get on the train.
喂～喂～那孩子想上车
Come on!
快跑!
Hurry up!
快!
We have to stop the train.
我们必须让车停下来!
-I don't know how. -Pull the emergency brake!
- 不知道怎么办 - 去拉紧急刹车
Who in the blazes applied that emergency brake?.!
是谁拉了紧急刹车?
He did.
是他!
You.
你!
In case you didn't know, that cord is for emergency purposes only.
如果你到现在还不知道 那是紧急时刻专用的刹车
And in case you weren't aware, tonight is Christmas Eve.
你没有注意今晚是圣诞夜吧
And in case you hadn't noticed, this train is on a very tight schedule.
还有你难道没注意,我们正在赶时间
Now, young man, Christmas may not be important to some people...
小伙子,圣诞节对你来说或许不重要…
...but it is very important to the rest of us!
但是对我们来说很重要
But-- But--
但是…但是…
He was just trying to stop the train so that kid could get on.
他只是想停住车, 好让那个男孩儿上车
I see. Young man, is that what happened?.
我明白了 小伙子,是这样吗?
Well....
好吧
Let me remind you we are on a very tight schedule.
让我提醒你,现在时间很紧
And I've never been late before...
以前从没迟到过…
...and I am certainly not going to be late tonight.
今晚也绝对不能
Now, ecerybody, take your seats, please!
现在,大家回位子上坐好
Thank you.
谢谢
Your attention, please.
大家注意…
Are there any Polar Express passengers in need of refreshment?.
车上的人,有谁需要用点心?
-Me! Me! Me! -I thought so.
- 我! 我! 我! - 我想也是的
-Hot, hot -Oh, we got it
# 呜 我们有 #
-Hey, we got it
# 嘿 我们有 #
-Hot, hot -Say, we got it
# 说 我们有 #
Hot chocolate Hot, hot
# 热巧克力,热腾腾 #
-Oh, we got it -Hot, hot
# 噢 我们有 #
-So we got it
# 所以 我们有 #
Yo, we got it
# 哟 我们有 #
-Hot chocolate -Here we 've only got one rule
- # 热的巧克力 # - # 只有一个原则 #
Never, ever let it cool
# 决不让食物凉了 #
Keep it cooking in the pot
# 一直在锅里热着 #
-Then you got -Hot chocolate
# 就有了热巧克力 #
-Hot, hot -Oh, we got it
# 噢 我们有 #
-Hey, we got it
# 嘿 我们有 #
-Hot, hot -Say, we got it
# 说 我们有 #
Hot chocolate Hot, hot
# 热腾腾的巧克力 #
-Oh, we got it -Hot, hot
# 呦 我们有 #
-So we got it
# 所以 我们有 #
Yo, we got it
# 哟 我们有 #
-Hot chocolate -Here we only got one rule
- # 热的巧克力 # - # 只有一个原则 #
Here we only got one rule
# 只有一个原则 #
Never, ever let it cool
# 决不让食物凉了 #
Keep it cooking in the pot
# 一直在锅里热着 #
Soon you got hot chocolate
# 马上就上了 #
-Hot, hot -Hey, we got it
# 嘿 我们有 #
-Oh, we got it
#  我们有 #
-Hot, hot - Yeah, we got it
# 耶 我们有 #
-Oh, we got it
# 呜 我们有 #
-Oh, we got it -Hot, hot
# 我们有热巧克力 #
You know, Montezuma, the king of the Aztecs...
知道吗…古阿兹塔克人的国王…
...would drink 50 quarts of hot chocolate every day.
一天要喝50大杯热巧克力
It was thick as mud and red. He put chili pepper in instead of sugar.
颜色像红泥浆,因为他们不放糖 而是放红辣椒粉…
-Get it?. Hot chocolate?. -How do you know?. That's not true.
-“辣”巧克力…懂吧? - 你怎么知道的?这不可能
-Where you going with that?. -It's for him.
- 你要拿去哪儿? - 是给他的
-I don't think we're to leave our seats. -It's a violation of safety regulations...
我想我们不该离开座位 对呀,这违反铁路交通规则…
...for a kid to cross moving cars without a grown-up.
儿童必须有大人陪伴才能跨越车厢
I think I'll be okay.
我想不会有事儿的
Are you sure?.
你确定?
What about this lad in the back?. Did he get any refreshment?.
后车厢的那个小伙子…喝过了吗?
Well, let's take some to him, by all means.
想办法拿去给他吧!
Watch your step, now. Watch your step.
小心走，注意，小心走
She forgot her ticket.
她忘了车票
It hasn't been punched.
车票还没打过洞
What are you doing?. You're gonna get us in trouble!
喂…你想干嘛? 会给大家带来麻烦的
Young lady, forgice me.
请原谅，小姐
I believe I have neglected to punch your ticket.
我想我忘了把你的车票打洞
May l?.
请
I left my ticket right here on the seat.
我刚把车票留在座位上
-But it's gone. -You mean...
- 但是不见了 - 你是说…
...you have lost your ticket.
你把车票弄丢了
She didn't lose her ticket.
不是她弄丢了
I did.
是我
I was trying to return it to you.
我只是想拿去还你
But the wind blew it out of my hand.
但是风把它从我手中吹走了
You can hace my ticket.
我的车票给你
These tickets are not transferable.
车票是不能过给别人
Young lady...
小姐
...you will just have to come along with me.
你得跟我来
You know what's gonna happen now?. He's gonna throw her off the train.
你们知道会发生什么事吧? 他会把她丢出火车
He's gonna probably throw her off the rear platform.
他大概会在车尾把她扔出去
Standard procedure. That way, she won't get sucked under the wheels.
这是规矩 这样就不会被轮子压到
They may slow the train down, but they're never gonna stop it.
他们或许会把车子放慢 但绝对不会停车
Stop it?.
停车?
That's it! I hace to stop the train again.
有啦!我必须再把车停下来
No, please, don't do that again.
不,等等,不要再做了
Where'd they go?.
他们去哪儿了?
What happened to them?.
他们怎么啦?
Please, she's in big trouble. You hace to help me.
拜托…她有麻烦 你一定要帮我
Hey!
喂!
I found your ticket! Wait!
我找到你的车票了!
Wait!
等等!
I hace your ticket!
我有你的车票!
Is there something I can do for you?.
有啥需要我效劳的吗?
I'm looking for a girl.
我在找一个女孩儿
A gi--?.
一个…哈哈…
Ain't we all?.
大家都要找女孩儿…哈哈
I hace her ticket.
我有她的车票
Well, lookie. Lookie here. What is this?
瞧瞧…瞧瞧 这是什么?
This is an official, authentic, genuine ticket to ride.
这是官方,正式,真正的乘车用车票
You better keep this in a safe place, young man.
你得好好保管它,小伙子
If I was you....
如果我是你…
I keep all my caluables right here.
就把贵重物品藏在这里
Right here in the old size 12.
藏在13号旧鞋底
Experience shows this is the safest place.
经验告诉我,这儿最安全
Not that I hace much use for those.
其实我不在乎什么车票
Tickets.
车票
I ride for free.
我都  免费的车
Oh, yeah, yeah. I hop aboard this rattler any time I feels like it.
对了…我随时想搭这班车就搭
I own this train. Oh, yeah.
这车是我的
It's like I'm the king of this train. Yeah. The king of the Pol Ex.
就好像我是这车的主儿 极地特快的主人
In fact, I am the king of the North Pole!
事实上,我是整个北极的主儿
Oh, where's my manners? Sit, sit. Sit.
我怎么忘了礼貌,请坐,请坐
Take a load off.
请坐,别客气
Hey, would you like some Joe?.
来点儿咖啡吧?
Nice hot refreshment. Perfect for a cold winter's night.
这么冷的天 来点儿热呼呼的提提神
There. Bless you.
祝福你
What about Santa?.
圣诞老人是怎么回事?
-Santa?. -Isn't he the king of the North Pole?.
- 圣诞老人? - 他不是北极的主儿吗?
You mean this guy?.
你是说…这家伙?
What exactly is your persuasion on the big man?.
那你说他是怎么回事 我是成人,直说无仿
Since you brought him up.
既然你提到了
Well, l....
我…
I want to beliece.
我愿意相信是真的
-But-- -But you don't wanna be bamboozled.
- 但是… - 但是你不想被骗
You don't wanna be led down the primrose path.
你不想被人耍着玩
You don't wanna be conned or duped, have the wool pulled ocer your eyes.
你不想被欺,被瞒,被蒙着眼睛
Hoodwinked. You don't wanna be taken for a ride, railroaded.
你不想被逼上火车
Seeing is believing.
眼见为实
Am I right?.
我说的对吗?
But what about this train?.
那这火车又是怎么回事?
What about it?.
你想问啥?
We're all really going to the North Pole...
我们真的要去北极?
...aren't we?.
不是吗?
Are you saying that this is all just a dream?.
你是说…这…只是个梦?
You said it, kid. Not me.
是你说的…孩子…不是我说的
So let's go find that girl.
那…咱们去找那女孩儿吧
One other thing.
还有…
Do you believe in ghosts?.
你相信有鬼吗?
Interesting.
真有趣
Wait.
等等
I hace to wake up.
我得醒过来
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up.
醒醒…醒醒…
Kid!
孩子！
Kid, get your head out of the clouds!
孩子，离开那里！
Wake up, kid!
醒醒,孩子
There's no sleepwalking on the Polar Express.
车顶上可不能梦游
We gotta jump them knuckles.
我们得跳车厢
Come on, kid. Flip my shoulders.
快…孩子,坐上我的肩
Grab my lily.
抓住我
That skirt you're chasing must have moved ahead.
你的衣服到前面去了
-We gotta hightail it to the hog, pronto. -To the hog?.
- 我们得到猪头那儿去,快 -“猪头”?
The engine. The engine, you tenderfoot.
引擎…就是引擎 你是个新手
We gotta make the engine before we hit Flat Top Tunnel.
我们得在车开到平顶山洞前 到达车头的引擎室
How come?.
怎么做?
So many questions.
这么多问题!
There is but one inch of clearance between the roof of this rattler...
平顶山洞的顶和车顶…
...and the roof of Flat Top Tunnel.
只有一英寸宽
Savvy?.
明白吗?
It's just the run up to the hump, kid.
车要上坡了,孩子
This will be interesting.
好玩的来了
Get back on, kid. Hurry!
快上来,快呀
Grab my muck stick.
抓住我的滑雪棍
There's only one trick to this, kid.
只有一个窍门
When I say ""jump""...
我说“跳”
...you jump!
你就跳！
You. I thought you got thrown off, and--
我还以为你被扔下火车了
-You're driving the train?. -They put me in charge.
- 你在这儿开火车! - 机师让我开
-The engineer had to check the light. -Here's the light. Careful.
- 他们要去检查车灯了 - 灯泡在这儿，小心
All right, now.
现在好了
I got it.
我拿到了
-How do you know how?. -It's easy. Come here, I'll show you.
- 你怎么会开? - 很简单,来,我告诉你
This big lecer here, that's the throttle.
那个大扳手是加速器
This little one here, that's the brake.
这个小的是刹车
And those are the pressure gauges.
那些是压力表
And that rope is the whistle.
那跟绳子是鸣笛
The whistle.
鸣笛
You wanna try it?.
想试试吗?
I've wanted to do that my whole life.
我一直梦想要拉一下
Hold still! Hold still! Don't move!
别动…别动
Look!
快看!
Stop the train!
快停车!快停车!
What?.
什么?
They want us to stop the train.
他们要我们停车
-Which one is the brake?. -He told me this was.
- 哪个是刹车? - 他说是这个
-Who?. -The engineer.
- 谁说? - 机师!
-The engineer?. This one looks like a brake. -No, he said this was the brake.
- 机师?这个看起来像是刹车 - 不是,不是,他说这是刹车
Are you sure?.
你确定?
Pull the brake!
拉刹车
Stop the train!
停车
Caribou?.
哈罗,鹿兄
There can be no Christmas without the Polar Express arriving on time.
极地特快到不了北极 圣诞节也泡汤了
Am I the only one who understands that?.
难道只有我懂?
You. I should have known.
我早该猜到
Are you bound and determined that this train never reaches the North Pole?.
你是不是一心 想让车子到不了北极
But look.
看!
Caribou crossing?
驯鹿过街!
I make that herd to be at least 100,000, maybe even a million.
我猜最少十万,或许百万
It's gonna be hours before they clear this track.
要它们全部让路得要几个小时
-A tough nut to crack. -We are in some serious jelly.
- 麻烦的事情 - 我们这下麻烦大了
-And a jam. -Tight spot.
- 非常拥挤 - 紧要关头
-Up a creek. -Up a tree.
- 小溪上去 - 树上去
-Lost in the grass. -I'll tell you what's grass: our a--
- 在草地里迷失 - 我告诉你什么草地，我们…
Problem solced. All ahead, slow.
问题解决了 慢…速…前进
We're going pretty fast.
我们驶的很快耶
Tell the engineer to slow down.
去告诉机师们放慢速度
Slow it down.
慢一点
Watch the speed!
小心速度太快
Jumping jeepers, the cotter pin sheared off.
跳开了,快把它抓住
-What?. -The pin.
- 什么东西? - 栓子!
-Where?. -There.
- 哪里? - 那里!
-Oh, no.
- 不妙!
-They can't hear me. -They can't?.
- 他们听不到我 - 听不到?
I don't like the look of this. Under the safety bar.
不喜欢这个景象 在安全栏下面
Is everything all right?. What should we do?.
不会有事儿吧? 我们该怎么办?
we are standing totally exposed on the front of the locomotive...
我们在车头前,完全暴露在外
...the train appears to be accelerating uncontrollably...
车一直在加速，无法控制
...and we are rapidly approaching Glacier Gulch...
我们快速冲向前方的冰峡谷
which happens to be the steepest downhill grade in the world...
这是世上最陡峭的峡谷
...I suggest we all hold on...
我建议我们都得…
...tightly.
抓～紧～栏～!
-The pin.
- 栓子
Jiminy Christmas, the ice has frozen over the tracks.
糟糕…车轨已经被冰覆盖
Hold on. Hold on. No, no.
不…不…抓紧…抓紧!
Come on. Watch your step.
快!小心脚下…快…
Come on, sweetie. Up you go. Up you go.
抓紧…快上来…快
Put your feet on here. On here.
脚放在这里，这里
Little adcenture, huh?.
有点刺激，是吗?
Young man, quick thinking on your part.
小伙子…反应满快的
Step to your left, please. To your left.
到左边去
Well, that is more like it.
呵…这才像话
What in the name of Mike?.
你们搞啥?
Look.
看!
Get us the blazes out of here!
快带我们火速离开
Turn this sled around.
让车滑开
Look there.
看那里
Tracks.
车轨
Dead ahead.
正前方
Right.
右
Left.
左
Hang a Louie.
打直
Toss a Ritchie.
拉掣阀
Port astern.
拉手
To the starboard.
放慢
-My slipper. -You're gonna lose your ticket.
- 我的拖鞋 - 你的车票要掉了
It's not my ticket, it's yours.
不是我的,是你的
-It's my ticket?. -Yes.
- 我的? - 对!
Right. Keep up with me. Left.
右…跟着我…左…
Right. Left.
右…左…
Right.
右…
Left.
左…
Left. Right.
左…右
-Oh, no!
- 噢，糟糕！
Brace yourselces!
抓紧了
Well, that's more like it.
呵…这才像话
Thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you. I can't believe you found my ticket.
真不敢相信,你帮我找到车票
Did someone say they found a ticket?.
谁说…找到…车票了?
Well, in that case.... Tickets, please.
这么说…车票拿来吧
Thank you.
谢谢
-""L-E""?. -Just like that know-it-all kid.
-“L-E”? - 和那个万事通的一样
Watch your step. Tricky walking up here.
走路小心
It's mighty slick. Mighty slick, I tell you.
提醒你,上坡时,路很滑
There you go. What did I tell you?.
我刚说啥来着!?
Years ago, on my first Christmas Ece run,I was up on the roof making my rounds...
很久以前 我首次圣诞夜之旅 我在车顶巡视…
when I slipped on the ice myself.
也踩到冰滑了一下
I reached out for a hand iron, but it broke off. I slid and fell.
我伸手去抓栏杆 但栏杆断了,就滑倒了
And yet, I did not fall off this train.
但是没有掉下车去
Someone saved you?.
某人救了你?
Or something.
也可能是某“物”
An angel.
天使
Maybe.
或许
Wait. Wait.
等等…
What did he look like? Did you see him?.
他长的什么样子? 你看到他了吗?
No, sir. But sometimes seeing is believing.
没有,有时…眼见为实
And sometimes the most real things in the world are the things we can't see.
有时…最真实的我们却看不见
The forsaken and the abandoned.
这些被遗弃的
Mind your step, now. These poor toys have suffered enough...
小心走 这些可怜的玩具受了不少罪…
being left to rust and decay in the back alleys and cacant lots of the world.
被世人到处抛弃,自生自灭
-What are they doing here?. -It's a new concept the boss came up with.
它们怎么会在这儿?
Instead of being thrown away, they're collected. Refurbished.
与其丢弃它们 不如收集起来修补一下
He calls it ""rebicycling."" Something like that.
他说这是循环 反覆,再生什么的
Makes me wanna cry...
真令人伤心
...seeing toys that were treated this way.
看到它们这样被虐待
These hopelessly entangled string puppets and marionettes...
这些吊绳都打结的木偶问题才大
pose a particular problem. We found the nimble fingers of our work force
我们在北极处理这些玩具的人员…
here at the North Pole are best for working out those knots and tangles.
为了打开绳结,可费尽脑筋了…
Thank you. Double-locked here.
谢谢你，这里双保险
You are just like me, my friend.
朋友,你就像我一样…
A scrooge!
一个捣蛋鬼
Ebenezer Scrooge.
埃比尼泽捣蛋鬼
North Pole, Santa Claus, this train...
捣蛋鬼从来不信什么…
...it's all a bunch of humbug. A bout of indigestion.
圣诞节,北极,圣诞老人…等等 全是难以置信,骗人的玩意儿
Oh, yeah. I know what you are.
喔,我是到你是啥…
You're a doubter.
你是个“怀疑论”者
A doubter. You don't believe!
你怀疑,你不相信…
You're a doubter! You don't beliece!
你是怀疑论者! 你不相信
You missed it.We rode down some really sharp hills.
你错过好戏啦 我们爬过陡坡
We were on what looked like a frozen lake. But I know it was just an optical illusion.
然后经过似乎结冰的湖面
He said the train was on ice. I said it's impossible--
他说车子是走在冰上 我说这不可能…
You can't put a train track-- Where you going now?.
因为车轨不可能… 你去哪里?
I'm wishing on a star
# 我对星星许愿 #
And trying to believe
# 试着去相信 #
That even though it's far
# 虽然很遥远 #
He'll find me Christmas Eve
# 但确有圣诞夜 #
I guess that Santa 's busy
# 我猜圣诞老人很忙 #
'Cause he's never come around
# 因为他从未来过 #
I think of him When Christmas comes to town
# 圣诞节来临时,我就会想到他 #
The best time of the year
# 那是一年中最好的时光 #
When everyone comes home
# 所有的人都回家了 #
With all this Christmas cheer
# 在圣诞节的气氛下 #
It's hard to be alone
# 是不该独自渡过的 #
Putting up the Christmas tree With friends who come around
# 朋友们都聚在一起竖起了圣诞树 #
It's so much fun When Christmas comes to town
# 圣诞节来时,真是有趣 #
Presents for the children Wrapped in red and green
# 孩子们的礼物包五颜六色 #
All the things I've heard about But never really seen
# 这些我都听过,却没见过 #
No one will be sleeping
# 圣诞夜没人会睡觉 #
On the night of Christmas Eve
# 圣诞夜的晚上 #
Hoping Santa 's on his way
# 翘首盼望圣诞老人降临 #
When Santa 's sleighbells ring
# 当他雪橇上的铃声响起 #
I listen all around
# 我仔细听 #
The herald angels sing
# 当天使唱起圣歌 #
I never hear a sound
# 我却从来都听不见 #
And all the dreams of children
# 孩子们的其他梦想 #
Once lost will all be found
# 曾逝去的会再寻回 #
That's all I want When Christmas comes to town
# 当圣诞来时，这就是我所有的祈望 #
Look.
看呀
The northern lights.
北极光
Hey. You three.
喂,你们叁个
We just crossed it.
我们刚经过…
Latitude 6622'. The Arctic Circle.
北纬66度33分…北极圈
And do you see?. Those lights in the distance.
你们看到远方的极光吗?
They look like the lights of a strange ocean liner sailing on a frozen sea.
看起来像大货船航行在 结冰的海上所发出奇异的光芒
There...
那…
...is the North Pole.
就是北极
It's a magic carpet on a rail It never takes a rest
地上有魔毯 从来没有休息过
flying through The mountains and the snow
飞过高山和白雪
You can ride for free and join the fun If you just say yes
只要你愿意 就可以免费加入，享受快乐
'Cause that's the way things happen On the Polar Express
在极地特快上 事情就是这样子的
Whoo, whoo, the whistle blows That's the sound of her singing
呜~呜~汽笛响 是她唱歌的声音
Ding, ding, the bell will ring Golly, look at her go
叮~叮~铃声响 天哪，看着她走
You wonder if you'll get there soon Anybody's guess
你觉得如果我们很快到达 谁来猜一猜…
'Cause that's the way things happen On the Polar Express
在极地特快上 事情就是这样子的
When we get there We'll scream, ""Yay!""
当我们到那里 就会尖叫，“噢，耶”
We'll arrive with A bang, bang, bang
我们到达那里 附和着邦~邦~邦
Boom, boom, boom Laughing all the way
还有噗~噗~噗 路上一直说笑着
We made it. With five minutes to spare.
到了! 比预定时间 还早5分钟!
There should be elces. Where are the elces?.
精灵呢? 他们在哪儿?
Yeah, where are the elces?.
对呀,精灵在哪儿?
They are gathering in the center of the city.
他们都聚集在市中心
That is where Santa will give the first gift of Christmas.
圣诞老人就在那儿 给出圣诞节的第一个礼物
Who gets the first gift of Christmas?.
谁会拿到圣诞节的第一个礼物?
He will choose one of you.
他会在你们之中…选一个
-Look. -Elces!
- 看! - 精灵!
All right. All right, ladies and gentlemen.
听好咯…听好咯…先生女士们
Two columns, if you please.
请大家排成两队
Shorter in the front, taller in the rear.
矮的排前面,高的排后面
Even-numbered birthdays on the right, odd-numbered on the left.
偶数生日在右边,奇数生日在左边
No pushing. No pushing. But let's not dilly-dally.
不可以推人,不要到处闲逛
It's fice minutes to midnight.
还有5分钟才到午夜
Hey, what gives?. It was five minutes till midnight four minutes ago.
怎么算的呀! 4分钟前也是剩5分钟!
Exactly. Columns of two.
没错! 排成两排…
-One, two. -Excuse me.
- 一排…两排 - 对不起
-Question. -What about him?.
- 有问题吗? - 他怎么办?
No one is required to see Santa.
没人会被强迫去见圣诞老人
Ladies and gentlemen, you do not hace to hold hands...
先生女士们,你们不需要牵手
- Come on. -...but please remain in your columns...
- 快点! - 走的过程中…
...while we are in transit.
请不要离开队伍…
-Look, you have to come with us. -She's right.
- 你必须跟我们走 - 她说的对
Christmas just doesn't work out for me. Never has.
我从来信不圣诞节
But Christmas is such a wonderful, beautiful time.
但是圣诞节是多么美好的时光
It's a time for giving and being thankful, for friends and family.
和朋友家人享受施与受的感恩
People hang decorations and lights. Santa leaces presents under our Christmas trees.
大家用饰品和灯来装饰圣诞树 圣诞老人也会把礼物留在树下
Christmas just...
只是我…
...doesn't work out for me.
从来信不圣诞节
Look, I don't know if Christmas is gonna work out for you or not...
听着…我不管你信不信圣诞节
...but this is Christmas Eve. Don't stay here by yourself.
今晚是圣诞夜,不要独自一人
Yes, come with us.
对,跟我们走
We'll go together.
我们一起去
Oh, no.
不好
We're gonna be okay.
我们会平安无事
Maybe not!
或许不会!
The emergency brake.
紧急刹车!
There's no brake. I can't find the brake!
没有刹车…我找不到刹车
Take a brake, kid.
休息会儿吧,孩子
How about a nice, good hot cup of Joe?.
热巧克力咖啡怎么样?
We're gonna crash!
快要撞上了！
We're spinning.
我们在转圈圈
You hear that?.
嘘…你们听到了吗?
The bell.
铃声
-What bell?. -The sleighbell.
- 什么铃声? - 雪橇上的铃声
-Sleighbell?. -Don't you hear it?.
- 雪橇上的铃声? - 听到了吗?
It's coming from that tunnel.
从隧道那边来的
That's the way we should go.
我们该朝那边去
Come on.
快呀
What?.
怎么啦?
-What?. -Come on.
- 怎么啦? - 快点
Come on.
快点
We're lost.
我们迷路了
Yes.
是的
-Yes. I hear it. -I hear it too.
- 是…我听到了 - 我也听到了
-I don't hear anything. -Okay, it's down this way.
- 我什么也没听到 - 是那边来的声音
Are you sure?.
你确定?
Absolutely.
非常确定
Why can't I hear anything?.
为什么我什么也听不到?
Get down and be quiet.
下去…安静
Yeah.
嗯…嗯…
Okay.
好的
Well, that was the wrapping hall, chief.
报告,这里是礼物包装中心
-Just finished the last one. -How's it wrapped?.
- 最后一个我也包好了 - 怎么包的?
It's wrapped in candy-striped red with a number-seven holly-green bow.
是用红色丝带和7号绿色花结
A number-seven bow?. When we're this close to liftoff?.
7号花结!? 我们也成了有钱人?
What are they thinking down there?. Are they meshuggener?.
他们在下面想什么? 是不是发疯了?
-What's the routing?. -Going to the States.
- 路线是什么? - 去美国
Grand Rapids, Michigan.
密西根州格兰拉比市
That's my town. I'm from Grand Rapids.
是我家的城市 我从格兰拉比来的
We got a troublemaker now. Just what we need.
我们有麻烦了 还真是时候!
Things aren't bad enough. What's his 20?.
事情还不至於最坏 他是不是20岁了?
Apparently, some kid from Maplewood, New Jersey...
显然是新泽西州枫树市来的一个孩子…
stuck some gum in his sister's hair.
把泡泡糖粘到妹妹头上
So, what do we do, chief?. Alert the big man?.
我们现在怎么办，首领? 通知圣诞老人?
We talking nothing for Christmas here?.
圣诞夜不给他礼物?
Look, it's.... It's almost Christmas, huh?.
听我说,圣诞节… 马上就到了,对吧?
We'll cut the kid a break.
原谅他一次
But put him on the check-twice list for next year.
但是,把他列入名单,明年复查两次
All right, boys.
好了，孩子们
Let's shut it down. That's it for this year. Come on.
现在关店 今年到这儿为止,走吧
-Hey, boss, are we taking the pneumatic?. -Of course we're taking the pneumatic.
- 首领,我们要乘子弹梭车吗? - 当然要乘子弹梭车!
It's the only way to get to the square on time.
这是唯一能赶到广场的方法
-Let's go. -And time is money.
- 咱们走 - 时间就是金钱
Ready, and mount.
准备…上车
Good. Close.
好了，关门吧
All right, get in.
上车吧
I don't know about this.
我不知道这个
I don't hear it. Do you?.
我没有听到,你呢?
No.
也没听到
I think we should follow those arrows.
我觉得该顺着箭头走
I thought there'd be a way out.
我以为这儿会有出路
We're gonna miss ecerything.
我们恐怕会错过一切
Hey, look.
喂～看呀
A present.
一个礼物
It's going to my town. To someone named Billy.
要去我的城市 给一个叫比利的人
-My name is Billy. -It's going to 1 1 344 Edbrooke Avenue.
- 我叫比利 - 去艾布克街11344号
That's my address.
是我的地址
Come on.
快点
Look.
看呀
It says, ""Merry Christmas, Billy. From Mr. C.""
上面说“比利,圣诞快乐…圣先生赠”
I think I know what it is. I wanted one of these my whole life.
我想我知道是什么 是我这辈子最想要的
Wait, wait. Stop. Look.
等等…停…看
But l....
不过我…
Those are the rules.
这是规矩
Something's got me.
有东西在拽我
It's got my leg.
抓住我的脚了
I can't hold him.
我抓不住你
Give me your other hand.
另外一只手给我
-I can't. -On three.
- 我不能 - 我数到叁
One, two, three.
一,二,叁
-Look. -It's still got me.
- 看… - 我还是被抓住了
On three again. One, two, three.
我再数叁 一,二,叁
-You.
- 你!
-What are you doing here?. -Same as you.
- 你在这儿干嘛? - 和你一样
Checking my presents. Making sure I'm getting everything on my list.
我在检查我的礼物 确定我清单上的都有
I found one present. All it had was stupid underwear.
我只有一个像样的礼物 其他的全是内衣裤
Look.
看
You may start your descent any time now.
我们随时开始下降
At your convenience, of course.
当然了，也要看你的方便
It's still fice to. I think we're gonna make it.
还有五分钟 我们能赶得上
Of course. It's been five to for the last hour.
当然! 一个钟头前,就还有五分钟
We got plenty of time. We got nothing but time. We got time to kill.
我们时间多了,我们什么都没有 就是有时间,我们还有时间来消磨
You know what?. I don't think we're gonna make it.
你知道吗? 我们可能无法平安降落
I may be just an old railroader...
虽然我只是个火车长…
...and know nothing about lighter-than-air craft...
我不知道怎么飞热气球…
...but from my layman's perspective, you need more altitude!
但是就我这外行来判断 你们需要再高一点才行
More altitude!
再高一点!
Altitude, please. A bit more altitude, please.
高度…我们需要多一点高度
Geronimo!
跳啊!
The Flying Elves.
飞精灵
They are specialists. Do not try that at home, kids.
他们是专家 你们可不能在家模仿
Do not try that at home.
孩子们,你们可不能在家模仿哦
We're not gonna make it.
我们恐怕过不去
A well-oiled machine.
维修良好的机器
All right, you stowaways.
好啦,你们这些偷渡客
-Party's over. -I was just following them.
- 派对结束啦 - 我们只是跟着他们
We fell in here by mistake.
我们是不小心闯进来的
Forget about it. We knew you was in there the whole time.
少来,我们知道你们一直都在里面
Come on, out you go.
快,出来吧
Let's go, come on. Step up, step up. There we go.
走,爬上来,爬上来
Not a problem. Come on. Watch your step. There you go.
行啦…没问题… 慢走…好的很…
So nobody gets hurt, here's how we're gonna get you guys down.
为了确定你们的安全 我告诉你们怎么下去
-This is simple. Why, I know-- -What do you know?.
- 简单的很,我知道 - 你知道啥!?
You're not supposed to be here in the first place.
你们根本就不该在这儿
But since it's Christmas, I'm gonna let you slide.
但既然是圣诞节 我就让你溜过去
Hey.
嗨
Been looking for you.
我一直在找你
There you go.
该你了
Watch your step.
小心点儿
Careful.
小心
Beautiful form. Beautiful.
漂亮
Nice to see you again.
很高兴又见到你
Cutting it kind of close, aren't we?.
这次很惊险吧?
I'll take care of this.
这个给我保管吧?
It's in good hands.
我会好好保管
Trust me.
相信我
It's the spirit of the season
# 这个季节的灵魂 #
You can feel it in the air
# 你可以在空气中感觉到 #
You can hear it if you listen
# 如果注意听就能听到 #
Everywhere So much care
# 任何地方都有关爱 #
Like a prayer
# 就像祈祷者 #
Whatever it is You need to share it
# 不管是什么，都可以分享 #
It's the spirit of the season
# 这个季节的灵魂 #
You can feel it in the air
# 你可以在空气中感觉到 #
Aren't those bells the most beautiful sound?.
这铃声是最动听的声音?
He's here! He's here!
圣诞老人就要进城了
Where?.
在哪里?
I see him. He's ocer there.
我看到了，他在那里
I can't see him.
我看不到
Doubter. Doubter.
怀疑者，怀疑者
Okay.
好吧
I beliece.
我相信
What was that you said?.
你刚说什么来着?
I beliece.
我相信
I-- I beliece that this is yours.
我…相信这是你的
Well....
嗯…
Thank you.
谢谢
-Me, me. Pick me, Santa. -What are you doing?. Stop it.
- 我…我…选我,圣诞老公公 - 你在干什么? 别这样
-Pick me, pick me. I want the first gift. -Hush.
- 选我,我要第一份礼物 - 别这样
Young man...
小伙子…
...patience.
耐心点儿
And a smidgen of humility might also serve you well.
还有,谦虚一点对你会比较好
Yes, sir.
是的
And you, young lady....
还有你,小姐
A lady of decision.
很果断的小姐
Full of confidence and spirit.
很有自信和热诚
Christmas spirit.
圣诞精神
Keep up the good work.
继续努力
Thank you.
谢谢
And Billy.
还有比利
It is Billy?.
是你比利
I see you'ce made some new friends.
你认识了很多新朋友
Yes, sir. I sure hace.
是的，我的确有
That's a lucky lad.
幸运的小伙子
There's no greater gift than friendship.
没有比友谊更珍贵的
And speaking of gifts...
说到礼物…
...Iet's have this young fellow right here.
就选这个小伙子吧
Now...
现在…
...what would you like for Christmas?.
你想要什么圣诞礼物?
Me.
我?
You.
是你
Yes. Indeed.
是的，就是你
The first gift of Christmas!
圣诞节的第一个礼物
This bell is a wonderful symbol of the spirit of Christmas...
这个铃铛充满了圣诞的意义
...as am l.
就像我一样
Just remember...
记住…
...the true spirit of Christmas...
圣诞的意义…
...Iies in your heart.
就在你内心深处
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Better keep that in a safe place.
好好保管哦
Hey, hey. Man alive, are you lucky.
喂～喂～喂～你真幸运
Pull, Comet. Pull, boy!
再用力拉一下
Prancer, that's a girl.
普兰斯，是个女孩子
Good boy, Donder.
好孩子，冬德
Now, Dasher. Now, Prancer and Vixen.
达实尔,普兰斯,冬德,维克森
It's everything I dreamed it would be.
就像我梦想的一样
Could all--?.
可能…
Could all this be nothing but a dream?.
可能全是梦吗?
No.
不是
To the top of the roof To the top of the wall
世界之巅…冲啊…冲啊
Now, dash away, dash away Dash away all
上车咯，上车咯
All aboard!
大家一起来！
One, two. One, two, three, go.
# 1-2-1-2-3 唱 #
Rockin ' on top of the world
# 在世界之巅摇滚 #
The place is hoppin ' There ain 't no stoppin '
# 山脊在跳动 # # 一刻也不停 #
Rockin ' on top of the world Lift your spirits, swing that girl
# 在世界之巅摇滚 # # 打起精神 一起来跳舞 女孩儿 #
Tonight, yeah
# 今夜就在世界之巅 #
Come on, shorty!
# 快呀 跳舞 得儿…耶… #
Show your tickets. Have your tickets ready.
拿出车票,准备好车票,谢谢
Remember to eat the five basic food groups.
记得每天吃5大基本食物
Ticket, please.
请拿出你的车票
And please brush after every meal.
饭后请刷牙
Remember to duck and cocer.
记得蹲下躲避 好啦,你们的车票
"" Lean."" Whatever that's supposed to mean.
LEAN(倾斜)! 啥意思?
"" Lean"" is spelled with four letters.
LEAN是四个字母
I belieced I punched fice.
我想我打了五个
Hey, are you saying I don't know how to--?.
喂～那你是说我不会…
I'm sorry. It says "learn." My mistake.
哦～对不起 原来是LEARN(学习),是我错了
Lesson learned.
学习到了
Ticket.
车票
That is some special ticket.
很特别的车票
Sure is.
是的
So can you count on us to get you home safe and sound?.
那…你能“信任”我们 把你安全送回家吗?
Absolutely.
当然
Me...
我…
...and my friends.
还有我的朋友
Ticket.
车票
It says "lead." Like "lead balloon."
是LEAD(铅)比方铅气球
I beliece it also is pronounced "lead."
我觉得也可以发音“lead”
As in "leader," "leadership."
这个字也是“领”的意思
""Lead the way.""
比方领袖,领导…
Follow you anywhere, ma'am.
领…路.谨尊您的领导,夫人
Ah, yes.
啊，好的
Young man with all the questions.
充满疑问的小伙子
Ticket.
车票
It says--
写着…
It's nothing I need to know.
我不需要知道
-Come on, let's see the bell. -Let's see it.
- 快…拿铃铛给我们看 - 让我们看看铃铛
-Show us the bell.
- 给我们看看铃铛
Yeah, let's see the bell.
让我们看看铃铛
It's gone.
丢了
-Where is it?. -I lost it.
- 在哪儿? - 我弄丢了
I lost the bell from Santa's sleigh.
我把圣诞老人雪橇上的铃铛弄丢了
It's gone?.
真的不见了?
Don't worry.
别担心
-We'll-- We'll find it. -Yeah, we'll find it.
- 我们…我们…会找到它 - 是的，我们会找到的
Yeah, we'll help you. All of us.
对呀,我们帮你,大家都会帮你
Yeah, let's hurry out and find it right now.
嗯,快,我们现在就去找
It's too late.
太迟了
Gee, that's really too bad.
真不幸
Really.
真的
I'm sorry.
我很难过
1 1344 Edbrooke.
艾布克街11344号
Next stop, 1 1 244 Edbrooke.
下一站…艾布克街11344号
Hey, where you going?.
喂～你要去哪儿?
Home.
回家
Oh, okay. Merry Christmas.
哦,原来,圣诞快乐
Thanks for stopping the train for me.
谢谢你,停车让我上来
Hace a wonderful Christmas.
祝你圣诞快乐
Watch your step, please.
慢走
And merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Look.
看
Santa got to Billy's house already.
圣诞老人已经去过他家了
Look, look! Santa got here!
看…看…圣诞老人来过了
Isn't that amazing?.
很神奇吧
It is amazing.
真的很神奇
I'm sorry about the bell.
真难过你的铃铛丢了
It was a really special present.
是很特别的礼物
Well, you know what they say.
你知道大家怎么说吗…
It's the thought that counts.
你内心怎么想才是真的
Yeah.
对
Well, see you.
那…再见了
Well...
那…
...see you.
再见了
See you.
再见
Watch your step, please.
慢走
Thank you.
谢谢你
No, thank you.
不对,谢谢你才对
One thing about trains:
关於火车…
It doesn't matter where they're going.
驶去哪儿不重要
What matters is deciding to get on.
重要的是你想不想搭车
Merry Christmas!
圣…诞…快…乐!
What?.
什么?
Wake up. Wake up. Santa's been here. Santa's been here.
醒醒…醒醒… 圣诞老人来过啦…圣诞老人来过啦
Hurry up. Hurry up!
快呀…快呀
Mom, Dad, wake up. Wake up!
妈…爸…醒醒…醒醒
Santa's been here!
圣诞老人来过啦…圣诞老人来过啦
Mom, Dad, look! He brought us all kinds of stuff!
妈…爸…快看 他给了我们这么多礼物
Look, a train!
看…一列火车
This is the beautiful-est, most wonderful-est Christmas ever.
这次是最漂亮最棒的一次圣诞节
Wait. Look.
等等…看
Here's one more.
还有一个
Has your name on it.
上面有你的名字
found this on the seat of my sleigh.
在我雪橇座位底下找到的
Better fix that hole in your pocket.
你最好把破口袋补好
Mr. C.
圣先生赠
-Santa. -Santa?.
- 圣诞老人 - 圣诞老人?
Really?.
真的!?
-Oh, that's too bad. -What's this?.
- 可惜了 - 这是什么?
Broken.
坏了
Sorry about that, sport.
真可惜坏了
Come on, kids. We don't wanna be late.
孩子们快吧,我们不想迟到
At one time, most of my friends could hear the bell.
曾几何时,我大部分的朋友 都能听到铃声
But as years passed, it fell silent for all of them.
但是大家过去的这些年头 都已悄悄逝去
Even Sarah found, one Christmas, that she could no longer hear its sweet sound.
甚至某年莎拉也突然 再也听不见甜美的铃声
Though I've grown old...
现在我长大了…
... the bell still rings for me.
还是能听到铃声
As it does for all who truly believe.
就像所有相信圣诞节的人一样